ILGWU Research Department Records 5780/209
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Research Department Records
1945-1995
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/209
9.5 cubic feet
9.5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Series I contains statements on issues related to the garment industry filed by the ILGWU between 1965 and 1995. Series II contains correspondence with non-ILGWU organizations and individuals, arranged alphabetically by correspondent or subject. Series III contains correspondence with ILGWU officers and staff, including staff of local unions, joint boards and councils, and regional departments and offices; Series IV contains files on miscellaneous subjects. Series V consists of the Research Department's outgoing letters between 1964 and 1991.
6791833
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 13, 2011
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 16, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Formed in 1937, the Research Department of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU) supported the administrative operations of the Union and coordinated the ILGWU's investigative operations. It provided union leaders with information on wages, working conditions, economic conditions, and other matters in the women's garment industry; analyzed information for the union; and monitored developments in the industry.
In addition to providing research for union leadership, Research Department staff prepared materials for Congressional testimony, presented cases on behalf of local unions to the War Labor Board, and worked to administer the Fair Labor Standards Act. At times, the director of the Research Department represented the ILGWU in national forums.
The Department also maintained an extensive library, collecting and housing documents from Union administrative staff that were deemed substantive and of lasting value to the Union, whether produced internally or externally. The information gathered by the Department was of particular value during labor disputes and contract negotiations.
Lazare Teper was the founding director of the ILGWU's Research Department, working in that position from 1937 to 1980. Born in Russia sometime between 1906 and 1908, Teper later studied at the University of Paris and earned his doctorate at Johns Hopkins University. He died in New York City in 1985.
Scope and Contents
The Research Department records reflect the department's varied functions, documenting its role in gathering and analyzing information for international and local union leadership, representing the union before government and labor organizations, and gathering materials of research, and oftentimes historical, value. Some segments of the records focus on one aspect of the department's work, and others include documentation across the department's functions.
Research Department director Lazare Teper's papers, for example, include files relating to the Wage Stabilization Board (5780/105). The department also maintained records focused on the National Coat and Suit Industry Board (statements of receipts and disbursements, label division reports, meetings minutes, bulletins to members, and other reports and resolutions), as well as some related legal files (5780/123). Also among the documents collected by the Research Department are the New York Coat and Suit Industry Reports between 1934 and 1960. (5780/168)
Parts of the Research Department records consist primarily of collected documents from ILGWU affiliates. In this way, they resemble and, in some instances, complement the parts of the Archives Department Records (5780/121, 5780/121 PUBS), records generated by local unions (Series III), and the general collection of ILGWU publications (5780 PUBS). Research Department records of this kind contain records of predecessor unions to the ILGWU and ILGWU local union records (5780/045), or the annual report, "Conditions in the Women's Clothing Industry" (5780/078).
Other parts of the Research Department records document all of the department's functions. These records include financial and administrative reports, meeting minutes, and correspondence (5780/056, 5780/209), collected printed material (5780/168), and ILGWU statements on issues related to the garment industry (5780/209).
This collection is divided into five series. Series I contains statements on issues related to the garment industry filed by the ILGWU between 1965 and 1995. Series II contains correspondence with non-ILGWU organizations and individuals, arranged alphabetically by correspondent or subject. Series III contains correspondence with ILGWU officers and staff, including staff of local unions, joint boards and councils, and regional departments and offices; Series IV contains files on miscellaneous subjects. Series V consists of the Research Department's outgoing letters between 1964 and 1991.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/045: ILGWU Research Department Records 5780/056: ILGWU Research Department Collected Documents 5780/078: ILGWU Research Department Reports 5780/105: ILGWU Research Department Records 5780/123: ILGWU Research Department Records 5780/168: ILGWU Research Department Records
Textile workers -- Labor unions; Clothing workers -- Labor unions; Collective bargaining -- Clothing industry; Collective bargaining -- Textile industry; Plant shutdowns; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Research Dept; Textile Workers Union of America; Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees; UNITE HERE (Organization)
6791833
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1992 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1994 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Statements filed by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), 1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, A-AL, 1973-1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, AM-AP, 1971-1991 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, AM-AP, 1971-1991 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, AQ-AZ, 1971-1986 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, AQ-AZ, 1971-1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1967-1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1967-1971 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union, 1976-1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO) Executive Council matters, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO), 1967-1970 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO), 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO), 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO), 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Correspondence, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO), 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Correspondence, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO), 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Correspondence, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO), 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Correspondence, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO), 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Correspondence, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO), 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Correspondence, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO), 1981-1988 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Correspondence, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO) Industrial Union Department, 1970-1985 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Correspondence, American Statistical Association, 1970-1978 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Correspondence, American Textile Manufacturers Institute, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Correspondence, American Vocational Association, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Correspondence, B-BEL, 1970-1987 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Correspondence, BEM-BN, 1972-1984 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Correspondence, BO-BZ, 1970-1983 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Correspondence, Bills, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Correspondence, C-CI, 1973-1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, CJ-CZ, 1970-1993 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, Canada, 1970-1980 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, Columbia University, 1970-1979 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, Cornell University, 1971-1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, D, 1970-1992 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, D, 1970-1992 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, E, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, England, 1971-1987 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, European Productivity Agency, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, F, 1970-1988 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, Federation of Apparel Manufacturers, 1978-1986 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, Ferster, Herbert (Drechsler and Leff), 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, foreign unions, 1967-1993 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, G, 1957-1985 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, Gewerkschaft Textile-Bekleidung (Dusseldorf, Germany), 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, H, 1967-1993 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, Harvard University, 1977-1988 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, International Brotherhood of Painters, 1972-1978 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, International Brotherhood of Teamsters, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, International Labor Office, Textile Committee, 1960-1980 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Correspondence, International Textile, Garment and Leather Workers' Federation (ITGLWF), 1967-1989 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Correspondence, International Textile, Garment and Leather Workers' Federation (ITGLWF), 1967-1989 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Correspondence, International Textile, Garment and Leather Workers' Federation (ITGLWF), 1973-1991 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Correspondence, International Textile, Garment and Leather Workers' Federation (ITGLWF), 1973-1991 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Correspondence, International Textile, Garment and Leather Workers' Federation (ITGLWF), 1973-1991 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Correspondence, Japan, 1971-1975 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Correspondence, K, 1977-1993 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Correspondence, L, 1971-1979 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Correspondence, M, 1970-1993 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Correspondence, Man-Made Fiber Producers Association, 1970-1980 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Correspondence, Man-Made Fiber Producers Association, 1970-1980 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Correspondence, Mennonites, 1945-1960 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Correspondence, Mountain Artisans, INC., 1970 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Correspondence, N, 1971-1988 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Correspondence, National Union of Tailors and Garment Workers, 1972-1976 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Correspondence, National Knitwear and Sportswear Association, 1971-1983 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Correspondence, New York City, 1974-1983 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Correspondence, New York State, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO), 1970-1984 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Correspondence, New York State, 1973-1984 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Correspondence, New York State, Department of Labor, 1970-1979 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Correspondence, New York State, Department of Labor, 1970-1979 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Correspondence, New York State Department of Labor, 1979-1990 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, New York State Council on Economic Education, 1985-1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, New York University, 1973-1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, North Carolina State University, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, Northern Textile Association, 1971-1980 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, O, 1971-1986 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, O, 1971-1986 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, P, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, S, 1971-1987 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, Schlesinger, 1971-1975 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, Small Business Administration, 1962-1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, Starobin, Herman (Director of Research), 1981 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, T, 1973-1990 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, U, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, United States Budget Bureau, 1959-1965 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, United States Census Bureau, 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, United States Census Bureau, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, United States Census Bureau, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, United States Congress (House of Representatives), 1974 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, United States Congress (House of Representatives), 1981-1985 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, United States Department of Commerce, 1964-1970 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Correspondence, United States Department of Labor, Department of Employment and Training, 1966-1976 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Correspondence, United States Department of Labor, 1976-1987 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Correspondence, United States Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Correspondence, United States Department of Labor, Wage, and Hour Division, 1961-1983 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Correspondence, V, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Correspondence, Wharton School of Finance and Commerce, 1958-1961 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Correspondence, Dubinsky, David, 1959-1966 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Correspondence, Stulberg, Louis, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Correspondence, Regional Office (Montreal, Canada), 1960-1972 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Correspondence, Regional Office (Montreal, Canada), 1973-1978 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Correspondence, Montreal Joint Board, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Correspondence, Montreal Dress Joint Board, 1966-1971 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Correspondence, Montreal Cloak Joint Council, 1963-1988 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Correspondence, Toronto Cloak Joint Board, Toronto Dress and Sportswear Joint Council, 1960-1978 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Correspondence, Winnipeg Joint Board, 1962-1982 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Correspondence, Puerto Rico Region, 1975-1993 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Correspondence, Puerto Rico Region, 1969-1974 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Correspondence, Puerto Rico Region, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Correspondence, Puerto Rico Region, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Correspondence, Puerto Rico Region, 1961-1965 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Correspondence, Western States Regional Office, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Correspondence, Los Angeles Joint Board, 1960-1969 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Correspondence, Pacific Northwest District Council, 1963-1968 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Correspondence, Southern Missouri-Arkansas District Council, Central States Region, 1964-1977 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Correspondence, Local 188, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 1960-1975 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Correspondence, Southern Illinois District Council, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Correspondence, Eastern Missouri District Council, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Correspondence, Michigan representative, Central States Region, Stark, Charles, 1974-1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, Midwest Regional Office, 1962-1972 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, Midwest Regional Office, 1974-1994 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, Central States Regional Office, 1960-1970 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, Central States Regional Office, 1971-1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, Missouri-Kansas-Nebraska-Iowa-Minnesota District Council, 1963-1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, Ohio-Kentucky Region, 1960-1980 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, Southeast Regional Office, 1962-1969 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, Southeast Region, 1970-1980 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, Local 415-475, Miami Florida, 1955-1972 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, Upper South Department, 1961-1983 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, New England Region (Massachusetts), 1966-1985 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, Connecticut locals, (New England Region), 1960-1988 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, Northeast Department, Pennsylvania districts and locals, 1961-1990 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, Northeast, Western Pennsylvania and Ohio Department, 1961-1982 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, New Jersey locals, 1965-1973 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, New Jersey Region, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, Eastern Pennsylvania Department, 1962-1978 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, Local 190, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1960-1968 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, Pennsylvania Organizing Department (Harrisburg, Pennsylvania), 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, Upstate New York and Vermont District Council, 1963-1969 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Correspondence, New York State District, 1965-1968 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Correspondence, Local 10, New York, New York, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Correspondence, Local 20, New York, New York, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Correspondence, Local 23-25, New York, New York, 1965-1988 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Correspondence, Local 32, New York, New York, 1964-1976 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Correspondence, Local 48, New York, New York, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Correspondence, Local 62, New York, New York, 1970-1977 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Correspondence, Local 62, New York, New York, 1960-1970 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Correspondence, Local 66, New York, New York, 1960-1976 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Correspondence, Local 91, New York, New York, 1966-1974 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Correspondence, Local 99, New York, New York, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Correspondence, Local 105, New York, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Correspondence, Local 132-98, New York, New York, 1960-1979 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Correspondence, Local 132-98, New York, New York, 1960-1979 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Correspondence, Local 155, New York, New York, 1971-1981 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Correspondence, New York Sportswear and Allied Workers Joint Council, 1978-1981 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Correspondence, New York Coat, Suit, Dress, Rainwear and Allied Workers Union, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- Correspondence, New York Cloak Joint Board, 1968-1976 (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Correspondence, New York Cloak Joint Board, 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Correspondence, Joint Council of the Cloak Out-of-Town Department, 1966-1975 (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Correspondence, New York Dress Joint Board, 1968-1972 (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Correspondence, New York Dress Joint Board, 1960-1967 (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Correspondence, Political Department (Dubrow, Evelyn), 1980-1995 (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Correspondence, Political Department (Dubrow, Evelyn), 1976-1979 (Box 5, Folder 45)
- Correspondence, Political Department (Dubrow, Evelyn), 1970-1975 (Box 5, Folder 46)
- Correspondence, Political Department (Dubrow, Evelyn), 1963-1969 (Box 5, Folder 47)
- Correspondence, Political Department (Wells, David and Waldinger, Roger), 1956-1981 (Box 5, Folder 48)
- Correspondence, International Relations Department and Archives (Mendelsund, Henoch), 1976-1982 (Box 5, Folder 49)
- Correspondence, Justice, 1968-1976 (Box 5, Folder 50)
- Correspondence, Legal Department, 1977-1990 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, Legal Department, 1962-1974 (Box 6, Folder 2)